Reza Soleimani

Front-End Developer

PROFILE SUMMARY

An Architect and Designer turned into a Developer. I bring unique Front-End Development skillset combined with my background in Architecture and UX/UI Design. I have experience developing responsive, user-friendly, and accessible web applications using Javascript, React, HTML, CSS, Firebase. I also created visual designs, prototypes, and wireframes using Figma, Sketch, and other tools.

PROJECTS

<u>Binge Fest</u> / React, RESTful APIs, Firebase, and CSS

Dec 2020 - During Bootcamp

- Smoothly connects 3 APIs and a corresponding real-time database in Firebase.
- Integrated a map using the Google Maps API and functionally connected it to the Yelp API.
- Used React and Firebase to dynamically load a selection based on the user's location and the shows stored within our database.
- Worked in a team environment that was fully autonomous, self-motivated, and delivered on deadlines set by the team.

So Serious! / jQuery, Sass/CSS and HTML

Nov 2020 - During Bootcamp

- Developed a card game using ¡Query and Sass preprocessor.
- Worked independently while practicing time management to meet deadlines set by the instructors.
- Delivered a fully responsive web game for a one week project.
- Added card flipping effect to enhance user experience.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer / Freelance

Apr 2020 - Sep 2020, Toronto

 Contributed to COVID-19 initiatives and related products by conducting user research, usability tests, creating user flows, wireframes, and high-fidelity mockups.

Architectural Designer

Eomac Ltd. / Apr 2019 - Mar 2020, Toronto Canamould Extrusions Inc. / Jul 2016 - Apr 2019, Toronto Penegal Trim & Supply Ltd. / Oct 2014 - Jul 2016, Toronto Solution Build Group Inc. / May 2014 - Oct 2014, Toronto

- Collaborated with the design and technical teams to develop concepts, sketches, and drawings of the products using AutoCAD, Revit, Photoshop, and Illustrator.
- Assisted various clients, received their feedback, and advised them
 of appropriate options to achieve their design goals.

www.rezasoleimani.ca github.com/rezaska reza.soleimani.ka@gmail.com 416.832.2825

SKILLS

Web Development: JavaScript, jQuery, React, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS/SASS, Firebase, Node.js, RESTful API, Git.

UX/UI Design: Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Additional: AutoCAD, 3D Max, Revit.

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp / Juno College (formerly HackerYou) Sep 2020 - Jan 2021, Toronto

Provided foundational knowledge in JavaScript, front end frameworks (React), and RESTful APIs. Worked in both collaborative and independent projects to translate requirements into polished web applications.

Eng. Software Skills
Enhancement / Humber College
Jan 2015 - Apr 2015, Toronto

BA. Architecture / Azad University Mar 2006 - Apr 2010, Iran

CERTIFICATES

User Experience Design /

BrainStation

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020, Toronto

Completed a series of workshops and created a mobile app.

User Interface Design /

Red Academy

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018, Toronto

Completed a series of workshops and designed a website.